

Software Engineer seeking roles in application development, Coding, Unit testing, Agile, Project management, data management, Production Support, C++, Core Java, C#, Python, Apache Tomcat, Spring, Data Structures, Algorithms, OOP, Design Patterns.Maven



Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: OPTUMINSIGHT INDIA Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Coding, Unit testing, Agile, Project management, data

management, Production Support, C++, Core Java, C#, Python, Apache Tomcat, Spring, Data Structures, Algorithms, OOP, Design Patterns, Maven, Rabbitmg, MongoDB, Spring Boot

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

7.5 years of IT experience in application development and micro services in C++, C# and Java.

Worked on Designing, Coding, Testing & understanding the functional and non-functional requirements of the applications to do effective OOAD model.

Significant experience of working with test-driven development and AGILE methodology.

Effective team player with ability to communicate at all levels of development process.

Work Experience

OPTUMINSIGHT INDIA as Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2020 to Till Date

KLA Tencor Software India Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer-3

Jun 2014 to May 2020

SMARTS Data Service (SDS):

A web service providing REST API for data management of a distributed deep learning platform. It's implemented in java using jooq, Spring, Jersey, Postgres as the database providing APIs to perform CRUD operations on structured data which includes Images, deep learning models. The service provides support for versioning on resources. The DELETE operation performs a soft delete on the requested resource which archives the resource instead of deleting from the database, enabling any future restore request on the resource, the archived resources are purged from the database after a configured time through a scheduled routine.

Electron Beam Review Workflow controller:

mailto:ashwin.d6d@gmail.com

This controller is part of electron beam review tool used for reviewing the defects in wafers. Workflow controller is an intermediate and controller software to decide whether to process an incoming message to subscribers or not, based on the rules defined on the rule engine. RabbitMQ is used for messaging and the entire system is developed in C#. SQL Server compact edition is used for the persistence. Classifier Management Service:

It's a SOAP based service implemented using the WCF in C#. It provides APIs to create a classifier, to get a list of all the available classifiers and to generate a report on performance of an existing classifier.

This service is a part of Automatic Defect Classification which provides infrastructure to collect lot data from different tools to central server, incrementally create classifiers, and attach to recipe when there is a classifier performance improvement.

Tally Solutions Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer Jul 2012 to May 2014

Education

UG: B.Sc (Maths) from Osmania University in 2009

PG: MCA (Computers) from National Institute of technology Karnataka, Surathkal in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C++, Core Java, C#, VC++	
Python, Postgres	
Apache Tomcat	
Visual Studio, Eclipse, Intellij	
WINDOWS, LINUX	
JMeter, CodedUI, TestNG, Putty	
Spring, Jersey and WCF	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Tamil				
Telugu				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time